ah
um our world our nation is divided
and as we look at what happened this
past week and what actually is still
going on we are seeing that there was a
hidden divide in our nation
um
I mean some would argue that but there's
a hidden divide and and you know people
are talking about we didn't know how
deep The Divide ran
and so our nation has divided our nation
is angry
our nation is afraid
there are a lot of emotions that are
going around right now have you felt it
um
let's pray Heavenly Father
bless us as we open your word
speak to us Lord and remind us who we
are as a people in Jesus name we pray
amen
our opening verse our scripture reading
was John 13.
John 13 verse 34 when you get there
please say Amen
the Bible says a new commandment I give
you unto you that you love one another
as I have loved you that you also love
one another by this shall all men know
that you are my disciples if you have
love one for another how many of you say
Amen
the world right now is lacking love yes
the world is lacking love and we can see
that the world is lacking love just by
The Divide just by the things we see
going on in our nation how many of you
can see that
the church
God says is to demonstrate what true
love is amen
amen that that amen was a weak amen the
church is to demonstrate to the world
what true love is amen so the Bible says
Christ says I want you to love one
another
as I have loved you
so shall the world know that you are my
disciples how many of you love one
another
oh man I didn't how many of you love one
amen praise the Lord praise the Lord
um
so I want you to
I've never done this before
and I hate when people do this but I'm
going to do it right now
look to your neighbor I hate that
I hate that it is so cliche but I needed
I need it for a purpose right now look
to your neighbor and say happy Sabbath
yeah I hate I hate I can't I cannot
believe I'm doing this right now but I'm
doing it I'm gonna do one more one more
look to your neighbor and tell them I
love you
okay
all right praise the Lord you guys look
good you guys look good
okay now now
amen amen amen everyone say Amen
praise the Lord okay now I have a
question for you if I uh if I said today
we were not going to have a sermon
but I wanted you to break up into small
groups
and we're going to discuss what happened
this past week
thank you
how many of you think that she would
leave here saying to your neighbor happy
Sabbath I love you
I I when don't fear not we're not going
to do that
but but but listen
just as there was a hidden divide
within our nation
something that perhaps wasn't caught on
the front on the surface it looked like
oh America the Great
could could it be that there is also
a hidden divide Within
the church
yeah could it be that that that the
church that is supposed to be the
example yes
the demonstration of Love could it be
that just as America the nation on its
surface looked like America the great
but then we saw this divide that no one
knew was really there and these emotions
that people did not really uh uh see
where there could it be that some of
those same things can be happening in
God's
house
how are we to be an example to the world
when
there may be a hidden divide
even within God's Church
in the Book of Ezekiel 33 turn there
with me if you will Ezekiel 33
and beginning with verse 1.
Ezekiel 33.
Ezekiel 33
and verse 1.
the Bible says again the word of the
Lord came unto me saying son of man
speak to the children of thy people and
say unto them when I bring a sword upon
the land if the people of the land take
a man of their coast and set him for
their Watchmen
hire him for their pastor
if when he see the sword come upon the
land he blow the trumpet and warn the
people then whosoever Hearth the sound
of the trumpet and taketh not warning if
the sword come and and take him away his
blood shall be upon his own head
he heard the sound of the trumpet and
took not warning his blood shall be upon
him
but he that taketh warning shall deliver
his soul
but if the Watchmen see the sword come
and blow not the trumpet and the people
be not warned if the sword come and take
away any person from among them he is
taken in his iniquity but his blood will
not require at the watchman's hand
beloved I believe that as God's people
we have a responsibility to speak truth
as your pastor I have a responsibility
when I see a sword coming
I have a responsibility
to speak
and so uh trust me I I am not you know
attempting to to uh instill uh fear or
or or doubt or anything like that I'm
just simply saying that as seven-day
Adventists we are a people of prophetic
destiny
we are people who understand or are
supposed to understand Bible prophecy
and when we see things being fulfilled
we have a responsibility to speak
and so I'm going to speak today
I'm going to speak today because beloved
I don't know about you but I see
that things are lining up
in such a way that prophecy
will be fulfilled
I don't know when I don't know exactly
how but I know that Satan is setting the
stage
last week I told you that we our nation
is in a terrible predicament because
because uh we have two different Visions
for this nation neither of which belong
to God
and whichever Vision won out was going
to take us in one direction or the other
either shutting down churches and and
forcing pastors to to to to be you know
to to do things that are not according
to the word of God or the exact
opposites
and we're in a place now beloved we're
at Seventh-Day Adventists we need to
understand where we are what's coming
and how we are to respond
Ellen White tells us that the final
events will be rapid ones
rapid ones
let me say this
right now
for the first time in a long time
all three branches of our government are
under the leadership of one party
and and I want you to understand this
because
let me pause right there
I will come back to that in a moment
Daniel chapter 12 verse 1 tells us this
that a time of trouble is coming
which will be comparable to no other
time in Earth's history how many of you
believe that yeah let me read something
else to you it's taken from the book
education page four two two eight
it says this the centralizing of wealth
and power how many of you see that
happening in America
the vast combinations for the enriching
of the few at the expense of the many
how many of you see that happening in
America
the the combination of the poorer
classes for the defense of their
interests and claims the spirit of
unrest of Riot and bloodshed how many of
you see that happening in America
the worldwide dissemination of the same
teachings that led to the French
Revolution all are tending to involve
the whole world in a struggle similar to
that which convulsed France
beloved what we are seeing happening
right now has been prophesied
what are we to do as God's people
what are we to do how are we to respond
because you know what
we don't live in a bubble
we live in this world we live in in
America and we've got to understand that
there are a lot of people and a lot of
emotions flying around right now
how do we as God's people respond
well first we have to know what's going
on so that we can know how to respond
correctly amen
so I've got a question for you how many
of you are familiar with the term uh
with the term dominionism
anyone ever heard of dominionism let me
explain that to you very briefly
dominionism is the teaching that is
making its rounds within Christianity
that that's God
desires
America to be dominated by Christian
principles have you heard have you heard
of this before
some of you have not looks like many of
you have not so if you get a chance go
home just just you know go on the
internet and type in dominionism and you
will see that there is this movement
it's also called Christian
reconstructionism and the idea is that
God
is raising up leaders to get into
government to turn our nation back to
God
okay
now now it it sounds like a noble thing
but but but for those of us who
understand Bible prophecy we know that
that is exactly what Bible prophecy says
is going to happen
in fact let me read to you from the book
great controversy
page 160 I'm sorry page 588. listen to
what it says here the Protestants of the
United States will be foremost in
stretching their hands across the gulf
to grasp the hand of spiritualism they
will reach over the abyss to clasp hands
with the Roman power and under the
influence of this threefold Union this
country will follow in the steps of Rome
in trampling on the rights of conscience
someplace else she says they will
repudiate the principles of the
Constitution I have a question for you
who does she say is going to lead out in
this work
Protestant
America
if you're going if you call that just
now just say Amen with me
not atheists
Seventh-Day Adventists not atheists are
going to lead this work out
not people who reject God and don't want
anything to do with God those are not
the ones that are going to lead this
workout the ones that are going to lead
this workout prophetically speaking are
the Protestants of the United States of
America if you're with me so far say
Amen
so so
in light of that God's people should
understand
that
the place in which we are now
is perfectly set
to see these prophecies
fulfilled
there is
a prophecy that I was not aware of I
don't know if any of you were aware of
this
um by the way uh I have a question for
you how many of you
love your pastor
now some of you didn't raise your hands
I'm just wondering what you know
if anything what may be going so I'm not
going to ask it again I'm just going to
pretend that I saw every hand go up and
I'm going to say praise the Lord
all right you love your pastor right and
listen guys
you know I mean if you know me you know
that I'm not going to preach something
just because I want to preach something
you know that what I preach is what I
believe amen you know that I'm preaching
not because I get a paycheck but I'm
preaching because I believe God has
called me
as a Watchman on the wall
and so please I am asking you right now
to lay aside everything Earthly
and I want you to focus on Bible
prophecy okay
I want you for a moment to to to lay
aside what you think about America and I
want you to focus on Bible prophecy
because that's what we are called to
focus on as a people amen so so listen
carefully
uh uh there is a prophecy that has
evidently been going around and has
sweeped uh has swept I should say uh uh
the the the the the religious right of
the Christians of of of of North America
how many of you know what I'm talking
about just let me see if any of you are
aware of it anyone aware of it a
prophecy regarding this election
to some people okay most people don't
know about okay I thought
I thought so uh let me read to you this
is called the Trump prophecy
yeah it's called the Trump prophecy now
you know it sounds funny and listen I I
it's this is not against people okay
this is not you know we're not talking
about Hillary we're not talking about
I'm not talking about individuals we're
talking about philosophies
are you with me all right so so check
this out
uh how many of you are familiar with
Charisma news magazine
okay very popular uh Evangelical
magazine it's all over the place you
know it's Wide Circle
1970 well this is from their magazine
this came out November 11th what's
today's date
12. this is yesterday
yesterday okay but it's going to take us
back to 2011. I want you to listen to
this
in April 2011 yes 2000 I'm reading from
the article now yes 2011 retired Florida
firefighter Mark Taylor received a word
from the Lord about the future of
America
is this ringing a bell now to anyone
but still at okay okay
god listen to what what it says in that
powerful prophecy God said Donald Trump
had been chosen to lead the United
States of America to bring honor respect
and restoration
if you want to know part of the reason
why so many Christians turned out to
vote for Donald Trump it's because this
prophecy was making its rounds
okay let me read on
that was back in 2011 and the prophecy
is online that the so-called Prophet
speaks this is online you can Google it
for yourself
but he goes on to say
um now now he's having this interview
with Charisma magazine so this is back
in 2011 but just this last week after
the election he has an interview with
Charisma magazine and so this is an
update in fact the article is entitled
an update on the prophecy listen
carefully
in it he says God has performed
everything he said he was going to do
Taylor said first and foremost I want to
give credit to the Lord Jesus who is the
spirit of Prophecy
because this isn't about me it's not
about one person this is a team effort
by the church whether it was prophesying
whether it was praying interceding and
fasting they Rose to the occasion and
God did exactly what he said he was
going to do it was a massive victory for
the body of Christ
that that's what he's saying okay this
is of this this is yesterday this
he goes on
Taylor also had a warning for the body
of Christ
we won the first battle but we haven't
yet won the war
the first objective getting Trump
elected has been accomplished but we
must continue to
I do believe the enemy may try a few
things to try and stop that he said it
will not be successful but it will be up
to the church talking about the
Protestant
we need to pray for and fight until we
get this man actually sworn in
Wiles the guy who's interviewing him uh
says this while said he believed there
will be intense spiritual opposition to
cleaning up America especially when it
comes to eradicating the deep-rooted
corruption and spiritual wickedness in
high places so check this out according
to the prophecy Donald Trump has been
elected to rid America of its corruption
now watch listen
Taylor and Wiles then discussed the
likelihood that there will be tribunals
convened in which Divine Justice will be
meted out
yeah you didn't hear that did you
you want me to read that again huh
let me read it again
now now mind you this is false prophecy
mind you but nonetheless I want you to
see what the the religious right is
thinking
okay listen
uh tailoring walls then discuss the
likelihood that there will be tribunals
convened in which Divine Justice will be
made it out they agreed the Lord was
telling them that these tribunals would
be of the kind not seen since the
Nuremberg trials of former Nazi regime
leaders after World War II
do you need me to read that again
yeah let me read it again
let me read it again let me read it
slowly
I don't want to paraphrase this
they agreed that the Lord was telling
them that these tribunals
would be of the kind not seen since the
Nuremberg trials of former Nazi regime
leaders regime leaders after World War
II
what I'm what I am actually hearing is
that these tribunals will make Nuremberg
look like a cakewalk because this
corruption goes so deep and it goes
worldwide
I think it's going to be an INT on an
international level
s added he believed the exposure of
corruption is only just the beginning
and he will continue and it will
continue for years to come he expects it
to continue throughout the Trump
Administration he said God is going to
use the president-elect to expose and
bring to Justice some of the most
corrupt people on the face of the planet
right now
in other words these tribunals are going
to be divine tribunals where where where
our government is going to bring to
trial people that are corrupt
oh let me read on
Tanner also said that the rooting out of
corruption won't be limited to
government the church will be cleansed
as well
it will start with the removal of the
Johnson Amendment which he said God
revealed to him as a demonic presence
but will continue with the rooting out
of churches and leaders who are morally
corrupt
okay
the silence is too silent
maybe it's shock I I I I it should be
because beloved listen I believe that
this is not a prophecy from God
however they believe
that this is from God
that God is going to set up Divine
tribunals to bring to Justice corrupt
people in government and corrupt
churches
this is what the true Army of God is
about he continues taking the fight to
the enemy taking ground and holding that
ground America's best days are ahead of
her I truly believe that this is just
the beginning this is just the beginning
this is just the beginning
beloved if you have read the great
controversy
if you have studied Revelation chapter
13.
you
you should realize that everything is
set
for the things we have always talked
about that will come to pass
everything is set
now I'm not telling you that it's going
to happen now I'm not saying that why
because I'm not a prophet right I'm just
telling you that from studying prophecy
and looking at what's going on and
seeing how these things are falling into
place beloved guess what if we as a
church are not prepared to meet this
Ellen White tells us that the work that
we should have done in time of peace
we will be forced to do Under the most
foreboding circumstances
are we ready
are we ready to give an answer
for the hope that lies within us
you see beloved we look at this nation
right now and we see yeah it's a mess
it's a mess people are angry people are
fearful people are worried people are
are I mean you know people are talking
about leaving the country and people are
talking about yeah get out of the
country
how are we as Seventh-Day Adventists
supposed to meet this challenge
I invite you to turn with me to the Book
of Ezekiel 37.
Ezekiel 37.
Ezekiel chapter 37 now before we begin
reading Ezekiel 37 I want to say this
if someone's mad right now
just hold your anger okay
because I'm going to come back to that
in a moment
I want you to listen to what I'm saying
I want you to listen to the word of God
Amen
listen listen
right now we look at this nation and we
see that this nation isn't a mess now
guess who says that not only the left
but also the right the entire nation is
looking at this nation and saying we are
in a mess right now we're in a mess
and the right they are fearful of
certain things they're saying you know
what look I mean look where our nation's
headed and look at all the things that
are coming into you know to our nation
look at all these other nations we have
to worry about and the left they are
afraid of you know look at look at look
at uh what the writers trying to do to
us it's like this principle of fear is
underlying everyone
watch this Ezekiel 37.
the hand of the Lord was upon me verse
one
and he carried me what did he do
everyone
yeah the Bible says the spirit of the
Lord carried me that is Ezekiel out into
in the spirit of the Lord and
and he calls me to pass by them round
about and behold there were
oh they were very what
and he's
can
and I answered O Lord God thou knows let
me give you a little background here
Ezekiel is a contemporary of the
Babylonian captivity
of the Prophet Daniel
when Ezekiel is is writing he is writing
to the captives
who have been taken captive by Babylon
the reason that they were in Babylon is
because they had ended up rejecting the
word of God
and so as you look at their condition in
Babylon
these were slaves in Babylon
in Daniel chapter 9 when Daniel is
praying he says to God O Lord unto us
belong confusion of faith in other words
they were discouraged in Babylon
and so God gives this Vision to to
Ezekiel to write down
and he says the Bible says he takes him
into this Valley to look at these bones
and the bones were what dried they were
broken they were brittle
let me share something with you hold
your place here in Ezekiel 37 and just
turn with me quickly if you will to the
Book of Proverbs 17 verse 22. what are
these Dry Bones mean proverbs 17.
verse 22. when you get there please say
Amen
Proverbs 17 verse 22 a merry heart doeth
good like a Watts medicine but a broken
what
Spirit dryeth up the bones how do you
get dry bones
through what a broken spirit that word
broken means Afflicted and Afflicted
Spirit a spirit that has been oppressed
hold on a second go over with me to
Proverbs 15. Proverbs chapter 15 and
verse 13.
Proverbs 15 and verse 13.
a merry heart maketh a cheerful
countenance
but by sorrow of the heart the spirit is
what
a spirit I have a question for you
as you look at the condition of America
do you see Brokenness
yeah we do see Brokenness don't we
we see we see people broken by
depression do we not we see people
broken by poverty yes we see people
broken by racism yeah
we see people broken by by political
factions we see people broken by by
depression by all these things we look
at this nation and we see whoa our
nation is
broken people are afflicted people are
suffering yes
and then God says to Ezekiel Ezekiel
look at these bones
can these bones live
and I got a question for you what did
Ezekiel answer
why did he answer you know
let me tell you why because he knew that
that
he didn't believe that they could live
their situation is so bad
yeah they're they're whatever they're
going through is so bad how can the Dead
live again
but this is God
so God could bring them back to life
but would he and so he ends up saying
I'm not going to say yes I'm not going
to say no I'm just going to say Lord you
know
you know
but never listen to me as Seventh-Day
Adventists I believe
that God is calling us to look at the
bones that are spread across our country
people who are fearful
who are afflicted who are worried who
are angry who whatever it is
leading them to be broken
it's leading our nation to be broken and
God says of his people come come with me
I want to show you something
I want you to look at the valley
this Valley is full of broken bones now
by the way who do we say these bones
primarily represent
they represented God too
God's people right Israel but where were
they
where were they Babylon so what what is
what is their condition in Babylon
broken bones Broken Spirits Spirit
people who do not understand people who
are confused and God says I want you to
look at these balls and I ask you a
question can these bones live
beloved when we see that it should bring
a smile wait a minute whoa God has
people in where Babylon and those people
are some of these very people that we're
looking at on the news
some of those people those very people
that God is talking about some of those
very people are in the right
some of those very people are on the
left
some of those very people are the ones
that are pushing to force pastors to
navigate people
yes some of those some of those very
ones are are on the right who are racist
against black people
but look can I keep it real
God is saying to us look at these bones
who you may think there's no hope
because you know what you know what the
right is doing
and the left is like
I want you to look at these bones
now I got a question for you can
and Ezekiel knowing the condition man
don't I mean think about it
think think about how how you know
people are wanting on one divide of this
nation feel how hopeless the other are
God
you're already on the wrong
you are already on the wrong side so
check this out he says to Ezekiel uh
come come I want you to see I want you
to look at the people that are broken
the people that are oppressed now check
this out do you know that Jesus hold
your place here in Ezekiel 37 go over
with me to Luke chapter 4 verse 8. Luke
chapter 4 verse 8 if we can just get
that up on the screen so you could stay
in Ezekiel that would be great Luke
chapter 4 verse 18. I'm sorry Luke
chapter 4
oh you're not putting slides upon us
Jesus comes he says the spirit of the
Lord is upon me because he has anointed
me to preach the gospel to the poor wait
the spirit of the Lord is what upon me
speaking did he not say that the hand of
the Lord was
upon him
look at what it says with Jesus
disappointed me to preach the gospel to
who
the poor he had sent me to heal the
the what
broken
yeah enough the broken
hearted
to preach Deliverance to the captives
of Babylon
and recovering of sight to the blind to
set at Liberty then that have been
bruised
oppressed
racially profiled
fill in the blank
whatever the issue is God says I've
called you to go speak to those people
who have been broken who have been
oppressed who are angry who are
frustrated this is exact beloved listen
to me we are in the most Prime position
to reach the world right now
it is at the height of messness
has made that word up
it is at the height
I mean it is so crazy what's going on
and yet God says I want you to look at
this Valley and I want to ask you the
question can these bones live
listen to me
Ezekiel does not say yes they can live
you know what a yes answer would have
revealed in Ezekiel
a dismissive spirit
all right catch this
yeah looks like they got problems but
you know ah whatever
get over the problems
no no Ezekiel Saw the condition of those
bones and was so moved by the condition
of the bones that he said wow Lord if
you do this it's going to be a miracle
because that's messed up
Ezekiel had empathy for the bones
I don't know if y'all are feeling me on
this man
because sometimes as Seventh-day
Adventist we can like say I love you but
not really show the empathy
not really so that we feel what you feel
we fear what you're suffering so look
but I've been listen there are people
who are afraid right now and you know I
say many Adventists are like hey what
are you afraid for don't worry about it
what's the problem
get over it
no no no no no no no you you can't do
that
when you do that you cut off the people
don't if they don't I hate cliche
sayings but I'ma say this one
uh how's it go people don't
care about how much you know until they
know how much you care ah I hate crazy
sings but you get the point
we have to empathize
with what people are feeling and fearing
and Seventh-Day Adventists that means
both on the right and on the left
we've got to come out of our selfishness
or our human thoughts and say all right
what is the right afraid of how can I as
an Adventist connect with them and let
them know I feel your pain I feel your
suffering but listen there's a better
way
how can I speak to those on the left and
say okay what are you afraid of okay hey
I hear you I'm not gonna minimize what
you're going through I'm not going to
minimize your fear but guess what
there's a better way how can I how can I
bring the two
together in one in Christ
but you see beloved we stand on this
side
or we stand on this side we become a
part of the problem
so
Ezekiel 37 verse 4.
no no no not verse 4.
wow
verse 1.
he carried me out in the spirit and set
me down in the midst of the valley
where did where did God take Ezekiel
put him right in the mix
of the dead bones
he didn't say Ezekiel I'm going to show
you the dead bones from a distance
I'm gonna show you the dead bones on
from The Mountaintop no he said Ezekiel
I need you to get down in the mix with
the dead bones
because you know what happens in the
story right look at verse 4 verse 4 says
uh and again he said unto me prophesy
unto these bones and say unto them all
ye Dry Bones hear the word of the Lord
thus say the Lord got onto these bones
behold I will cause breath to enter into
you and you shall
you shall live
you shall live but check it out guys
he doesn't tell Ezekiel it's all right
to do that from the comfort of your
Mountaintop somewhere
he says I need you to get down in the
mix with the people I mean with the
bones
I need you to come and and be among them
and dwell among them as one who desires
their good
I don't want you in your comfortable
Church while there no I need you
to know what it means to get down in the
valley with those who are suffering
and you know what many of us are afraid
of the valley
but but Psalm says yea though I what
what through the what valley of what the
shadow of death guess what guess where
Ezekiel 37 is unfolding it is the Valley
of the shadow of death
that's what's going on there death
discouragement Brokenness and God says
Seventh-Day Adventists
stop separating yourself from the cares
and the worries that people in the world
are going through identify with them so
that you can help bring them to life
I need you to get down in the valley
I need you to pull your sleeves up I
need you to not just say I love you
to not just think hey as long as I
prophesy from my Mountainside somewhere
that'll be good no God says the prophesy
works when you get down in the valley
with them
otherwise I would have just had you
speak from someplace else no he carried
him into the valley and beloved God is
wanting to carry us into the valley God
needs us as a church to recognize the
fears of minorities
whether they are Mexican or black or
whatever recognize their fears but say
Hey listen there's a solution
there's a solution I feel your pain I
feel your worries but guess what God has
something greater there is something
that God wants you to understand the
solution is the world has no solution to
offer you my friend I'm sorry to let you
know this
but guess what God has a solution
beloved listen to me on the right they
are worried about Russia and China
invading our country guess what you know
we can tell them guys that's not
according to Bible prophecy
you don't have to worry about that let
me share with you what the Bible
actually says in other words beloved
when we are able to identify the worries
that this world is going through that
this nation is going through as Advent
as we are in a very unique position to
be able to minister to both
you see beloved look the left is looking
at the right and saying if that's what
Christianity is I want nothing to do
with it and a seven day Adventist we
hold a unique place or we can say Hey
listen that's what not real Christianity
is about
it's not about forcing people to to
serve God no no no no look that's what
you may see from them but let me show
you a better way
God calls us into the valley and he says
I want you to speak and so the Book of
Ezekiel 37 verse 7 it says this so I
prophesied as I was commanded
verse 6 I will lay sins upon you and I
will bring flesh upon you
and cover you with skin and put breath
in you and you shall live and you shall
know that I am the Lord so I prophesied
as I was commanded and as I prophesied
there was a noise and behold the shaking
and bone came together to Bone man I
love that verse bone came together to
bone
there was a reconnecting of that which
had been separated
but when the spirit the spear God moves
bone comes together
with bone
verse 9 then he said unto verse 8 and
when I beheld lower the sins and the
flesh Came Upon them and the skin
covered them above but there was no
breath in them then he said unto me
prophesying to the winds prophesied son
of man and say to the wind thus saith
the Lord God come from the Four Winds or
breath and breathe upon these that are
slain that they may live so I prophesied
as he commanded me and the breath came
into them and they lived and stood upon
their feet and exceeding great Army then
he said unto me son of man these bones
are the whole house of Israel behold
they say our bones are dried our hope is
lost we are cut off from our parts
therefore prophesy and sound to them
thus say the Lord God behold all my
people I will open your Graves and cause
you to come up out of your Graves and
bring you into the land of Israel then
you will know that I am the Lord listen
to me
God is trying to tell us that when we
prophesy in the valley not from the
mountaintops
when we get down with people who are
suffering he says your word will have a
much greater effect
the Bible tells us that they stood upon
their feet and became an exceeding great
Army a great multitude
oh yeah
they became a great multitude but love
it listen to me we believe that at the
end of time a great multitude is going
to come out of Babylon
how are we going to get the great
multitude if we're not down in the
valley where the multitude are
that's where they come from
that's why God is calling us to go and
call them out of
Babylon
my people he says are in there
when you're looking at that at that man
on the right or that man on the left the
people that are in this nation divided
and they're doing all kinds of crazy
things carrying all kinds of crazy signs
riding in all kinds of crazy ways God
says look they look like dead bones now
I know that
but I need you to see them as a Great
and Mighty Army for me
at beloved when we can see that
and when we treat each other talking
about out there in the world when we
treat them like look I know what God has
for you I'm telling you we will be moved
with a passion that is born out of the
Heart of Jesus Christ
so so check this out uh we're almost
done okay so so just bear with me if you
will by the way
it is the message of the Three Angels
that we're to prophesy
message to Every Nation Kindred tongue
and people
together
people of all Races
tribes cultures
well who would have thought that
who would have thought that the answer
to racial divide
is in the first Angel's message
who would have thought that the answer
to division in so many different ways
isn't that is found in the first Angel's
message
beloved as God's people we got to know
who we are where we stand and listen
I said this in morning Sabbath School
the Bible says do not turn to the right
hand or to the left
okay
stay centered
on Jesus Christ
and when you're centered on Jesus Christ
you will be in a unique place where you
can minister to the right and to the
left
so so
last part of Ezekiel 37 verse 15 verse
15.
uh the Bible says here
uh um the Bible says moreover verse 16
moreover thou son of man take thee one
stick and write upon it for Judah and
for the children of Israel his
companions then take another stick and
write upon it for Joseph and the sick of
Ephraim and for all the house of is of
Israel and his companions and join them
one to another into one stick and they
shall become one in my hand
and when the children of Israel of thy
people shall speak unto thee saying what
will thou show us this mean it's by
these say unto them thus saith the Lord
God behold I will take the Stick of
Joseph
which is in the hand of Ephraim and the
tribes of Israel and his fellows and put
them even with the Stick of Judah and
make them one stick and they shall be
one in my hand and the sticks were on
thou writers shall be in thine eye in
thine hand before thine eyes and sail
and say unto them thus saith the Lord
God behold I will take the children of
Israel from among the Heathen whether
they be God and will gather them on
every side and bring them into their own
land and I will make them one nation in
the land of the Mountain of Israel and
one King shall be a king unto them and
they shall be no more two Nations they
shall and neither shall they be divided
into two kingdoms anymore at all
this is the same vision
it's taking two people who are divided
and bringing to them together in one and
God calls them Israel where are God's
people right now they are in Babylon God
says I want you to take these two sticks
and combine them into one to show you
that my mission is to unite all of God's
people into one movement
but as we close
we have a problem
because
if we are not United in here
how can we go give a message to the
world
to be United
there is hidden
how can we even dare open our mouths to
prophesy
to the dead bones
no no no you know what needs to happen
these dead bones
need to come to life
before we can go bring life to those
dead bones
these dead bones
need to connect
yeah yeah because now it's like I'm
telling you I know it I gotta trust me
let us break up in the groups and have a
discussion about this past weekend there
will be people living here saying and I
hate you too
don't call me it's over I cannot believe
how you can't you say
am I lying I'm not lying
yeah I'm talking about across our church
worldwide
how can we sow how can we appeal for
Unity in truth out there if we cannot
experience it in here
so beloved these dead bones
need to come to life these dead bones
need to stand upon their feet as a great
Army and when they do stand upon their
feet as a great Army where are they
standing they're standing in the valley
not elsewhere in the valley they're
saying all right we're going to get down
where the people are
we're going to mingle with those who are
suffering as one who does
and not dictate to them
and not to tell them you know what
you're feeling doesn't matter you know
get over it
no
no that's not what we do that's not who
we are as a people
but before we can do it out there we
better learn how to do it in here
we better learn how to do it in here my
appeal
Lord
bring these dry bones
bring these bones who who are who are
these bones in here who are under their
own stresses who are under their own
Sorrows who are under their own
discouragements who are under their own
fears help us to be able to relate one
to another
as we're discussing where our nation is
going help me not to look at my brother
in the church and tell him yeah you know
what you feel doesn't matter
help us to be more empathetic
with one another
pray with one another Unite with one
another and beloved when as John 13 34
says my people love one another and by
this shall the whole world know that you
are my disciples then when the whole
world knows oh yeah that's not the
that's discipleship right there those
are his disciples when the world knows
that I'm telling you we're going to see
a great Army
we're going to see a great Army
so
if it is your desire to number one
be United in this body
Lord help me to just put away the help
me to understand what you've called me
for as a seven-day Adventist help me to
understand my mission and help me not to
get caught to turn to the left or the
right but to stay centered on you and to
get down into the valley number one
number one connect with with people here
and number two get down into the valley
out there
if that is I'm just going to ask
you raise your hand say Lord that's me
that's me that's me
Heavenly Father
thank you for speaking to us
in Jesus name
amen
foreign